A Guide to the Office of the Messrs. Rockefeller records, Educational Interests, Series G FA316
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Colleges
  - Colleges - Princeton University - John D. Rockefeller 3rd - Printed Material, 1938-1948 (Box 84, Folder 596)
    1961 Trustees Minutes and Reports; 1948 Rules and Procedures of the Faculty; Retirement Benefits; 1961-1962 Facts About Princeton; Summary of Honorary Degrees, 1948-1958.
  - Colleges - Princeton University - John D. Rockefeller 3rd - Population Study, 1952-1955 (Box 84, Folder 597)
    John D. Rockefeller 3rd's 1952 contributions.
  - Colleges - Princeton University - John D. Rockefeller 3rd - Public Service Awards, 1951-1952 (Box 84, Folder 0597A)
    Setting up the program for special training of civilian government employees; selection of winners. Problems of awardees and of getting active support from Dulles and President Eisenhower. Attempts to get congressional legislation creating this type of training program. Photos of John F. Kennedy, Robert Goheen, and John D. Rockefeller 3rd. 1956 evaluation of program; 1960 changes in program. 1961 speeches by Dean Rusk and John D. Rockefeller 3rd at Awards Luncheon. Correspondents include James Mitchell, Harry S. Truman, Arthur S. Flemming, Sam Rayburn, Olin Johnson, C. Douglas Dillon, John D. Rockefeller 3rd.
  - Colleges - Princeton University - John D. Rockefeller 3rd - Public Service Awards, 1952 (Box 84, Folder 598)
  - Colleges - Princeton University - John D. Rockefeller 3rd - Public Service Awards, 1953-1956 (Box 84, Folder 0598A)
  - Colleges - Princeton University - John D. Rockefeller 3rd - Public Service Awards, 1953-1961 (Box 84, Folder 599)
  - Colleges - Princeton University - John D. Rockefeller 3rd - Public Service Awards, 1953-1960 (Box 85, Folder 600)
  - Colleges - Princeton University - John D. Rockefeller 3rd - Public Service Awards, 1959-1962 (Box 85, Folder 0600A)
  - Colleges - Princeton University - John D. Rockefeller 3rd - Public Service Awards, 1960-1961 (Box 85, Folder 601)
  - Colleges - Princeton University - John D. Rockefeller 3rd - Public Service Awards, 1961-1962 (Box 85, Folder 602)
  - Colleges - Princeton University - John D. Rockefeller 3rd - Public Service Awards - Printed Materials, 1952-1956 (Box 85, Folder 603)
    Reports, John D. Rockefeller 3rd's testimony at 1958 Committee Hearings on Training Bill; copies of various bills proposed.
  - Colleges - Princeton University - John D. Rockefeller 3rd - Public Service Awards - Printed Materials, 1956-1958 (Box 85, Folder 604)
  - Colleges - Princeton University - John D. Rockefeller 3rd - Woodrow Wilson School, 1947-1960 (Box 86, Folder 605)
    John D. Rockefeller 3rd's gift to school for public and international affairs; information re Woodrow Wilson Fellowship Program; General Education Board grant. John D. Rockefeller 3rd participation in Advisory Council and in Robertson Foundation created to finance and expand school. Reports and Draft Programs of the Robertson Foundation. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller 3rd, Everett Case, Brooks Emeny, Gardner Patterson, D. H. McLean.
  - Colleges - Princeton University - John D. Rockefeller 3rd - Woodrow Wilson School, 1961-1962 (Box 86, Folder 0605A)
  - Colleges - Princeton University - Laurance S. Rockefeller, 1936-1954 (Box 86, Folder 606)
    Laurance S. Rockefeller a member of Advisor Council of Aeronautical Engineering Department and of Department of Philosophy. Member of nationwide corporate advisory committee. Reunions; Princeton plans; invitations to meetings. Correspondents include Laurance S. Rockefeller, Harold Dodds, Dean Sayre.
    Open per BJA, July 19, 2004.
  - Colleges - Princeton University - Laurance S. Rockefeller, 1955-1961 (Box 86, Folder 0606A)
  - Colleges - Princeton University - Laurance S. Rockefeller - Contributions, 1939-1949 (Box 86, Folder 607)
    Contributions towards radio programs, aviation research, library, Third Century fund, philosophy department, Woodrow Wilson School of Public and International Affairs, expenses of reunions, publication of Forrestal diaries, University health fund, undergraduate housing, Engineering Quadrangle, and Campaign for $53,000,000. Correspondents include Laurance S. Rockefeller, Robert Goheen, H. W. Dodds.
  - Colleges - Princeton University - Laurance S. Rockefeller - Contributions, 1950-1959 (Box 86, Folder 608)
  - Colleges - Princeton University - Laurance S. Rockefeller - Annual Gifts, 1941-1960 (Box 87, Folder 609)
    Class of 1932 annual giving fund; Laurance S. Rockefeller gave $250 a year. Correspondents include Laurance S. Rockefeller.
  - Colleges - Princeton University - Laurance S. Rockefeller - Forrestal Memorial, 1950-1952 (Box 87, Folder 0609A)
    Rockefeller Institute property purchased as site for aeronautical research center. Fund-raising activities by friends of Forrestal. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. declines early contribution. Contributions by John D. Rockefeller 3rd, Laurance S. Rockefeller, Nelson A. Rockefeller. Purchase of Forrestal diaries for center. Progress of fund-raising campaign. Correspondents include Laurance S. Rockefeller, H. W. Dodds, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Daniel C. Sayre, Lewis Strauss.
  - Colleges - Princeton University - Laurance S. Rockefeller - Forrestal Memorial, 1952 (Box 87, Folder 0609B)
  - Colleges - Princeton University - Laurance S. Rockefeller - Forrestal Memorial, 1952-1960 (Box 87, Folder 610)
  - Colleges - Princeton University - Laurance S. Rockefeller - Department of Philosophy, 1936-1946 (Box 87, Folder 611)
    Laurance S. Rockefeller served on Committee of Departmental Alumni. Contribution to finance visits of outstanding philosophers. Laurance S. Rockefeller's interest in department personnel and program. Correspondents include Laurance S. Rockefeller, Robert Scoon, Gregory Vlastos.
  - Colleges - Princeton University - Laurance S. Rockefeller - Department of Philosophy, 1946-1948 (Box 87, Folder 612)
  - Colleges - Princeton University - Laurance S. Rockefeller - Department of Philosophy, 1949-1961 (Box 87, Folder 613)
  - Colleges - Princeton University - Laurance S. Rockefeller - Department of Philosophy Alumni Association, 1938-1942 (Box 87, Folder 614)
    Laurance S. Rockefeller treasurer of association; his contributions to association and to Department of Philosophy. Correspondents include Laurance S. Rockefeller.
  - Colleges - Princeton University - Steven C. Rockefeller, 1960-1961 (Box 87, Folder 615)
  - Colleges - Radcliffe College, 1950-1961 (Box 88, Folder 616)
    Laurance S. Rockefeller contributions to scholarship funds; other requests declined. Mary French Rockefeller's contributions to Radcliffe. Correspondents include Laurance S. Rockefeller.
  - Colleges - Radcliffe College, 1951-1956 (Box 88, Folder 0616A)
  - Colleges - Radcliffe College - Institute for Independent Study, 1960-1961 (Box 88, Folder 0616B)
  - Colleges - Radcliffe College - Institute for Independent Study, 1960-1961 (Box 88, Folder 616C)
  - Colleges - Rollins College, 1923-1955 (Box 88, Folder 617)
    Appeals for aid declined. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Willard S. Richardson, Thomas B. Appleget, Arthur W. Packard.
  - Colleges - Roosevelt University, Chicago, 1946-1959 (Box 88, Folder 618)
    President Sparling's attempts to get an interview. $5,000 Nelson A. Rockefeller contribution, 1953; other appeals declined. Correspondents include E. J. Sparling, Dana S. Creel, Edgar B. Young.
  - Colleges - Rutgers University, 1952-1958 (Box 88, Folder 619)
    Declinations of appeals for contributions to various Rutgers projects. Correspondents include Laurance S. Rockefeller, Murray F. Buell, Edgar B. Young, Dana S. Creel.
  - Colleges - Rutgers University, 1952-1954 (Box 88, Folder 0619A)
  - Colleges - Simmons College, 1942-1949 (Box 88, Folder 620)
    Appeals declined.
  - Colleges - Smith College, Northampton, Massachusetts
    Hope Aldrich's contributions, 1960-1961.
    John D. Rockefeller $100,000 conditional gift for endowment and buildings, 1901. No giving afterward until John D. Rockefeller 3rd's anonymous contribution in 1947. Margaret Sanger given honorary degree on John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s recommendation, 1949. Large 1950 contribution by John D. Rockefeller, Jr. as tribute to Mrs. Morrow. John D. Rockefeller 3rd's contributions, 1956-1959, as father of Smith student. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Starr J. Murphy, Mrs. Dwight W. Morrow, Mrs. Amanda Kane.
    - 1901-1950 (Box 88, Folder 621)
    - 1950-1959 (Box 88, Folder 622)
    - 1956-1961 (Box 88, Folder 622A)
  - Colleges - Smith College, Northampton, Massachusetts - Scholarship Fund, 1959-1961 (Box 88, Folder 623)
  - Colleges - Spelman College
    John D. Rockefeller purchases property for college through American Baptist Home Mission Society. Plans for expansion; appeals for aid. Racial conditions in Atlanta. Naming of buildings; college status in 1924. Invitations; selection of president; activities of Spelman graduates. Tributes to Rockefellers. Gift of Spelman portraits by John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Mary French Rockefeller a trustee; Winthrop Rockefeller address at 1959 commencement. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Laurance S. Rockefeller, Mary French Rockefeller, Winthrop Rockefeller, Frederick T. Gates, Starr J. Murphy, Dana S. Creel, H. G. Morehouse, Florence M. Read.
    - 1891 (Box 89, Folder 624)
    - 1898-1900 (Box 89, Folder 0624A)
    - 1901-1906 (Box 89, Folder 625)
    - 1922-1926 (Box 89, Folder 0625A)
    - 1927-1933 (Box 89, Folder 626)
    - 1934-1945 (Box 89, Folder 0626A)
    - 1946-1952 (Box 89, Folder 627)
    - 1953-1954 (Box 89, Folder 0627A)
    - 1955-1961 (Box 89, Folder 628)
    - Laurance S. Rockefeller / Mary French Rockefeller, 1947-1960 (Box 89, Folder 0628A)
  - Colleges - Spelman College - Printed Material, 1927-1964 (Box 90, Folder 629)
    Copies of "Spelman Messenger" containing articles or photos on Rockefellers; 1927, 1937, 1951, 1952, 1953. Pamphlet on Trevor Arnett; "Ebony" articles on Negro colleges.
  - Colleges - Spelman College - Printed Material, 1951-1964 (?) (Box 90, Folder 0629A)
  - Colleges - Spelman College - Contributions, 1947-1954 (Box 90, Folder 630)
  - Colleges - Spelman College - Contributions, 1955-1961 (Box 90, Folder 0630A)
  - Colleges - Spelman College - Contributions, 1958-1961 (Box 90, Folder 630A.1)
  - Colleges - Spelman College - Contributions - Gift from General Education Board, 1913-1926 (Box 90, Folder 0630B)
  - Colleges - Spelman College - Liberalization of Gift to General Education Board - 1930 Grant, 1930-1934 (Box 90, Folder 0630C)
  - Colleges - Spelman College - Successor to Miss Read, 1950-1953 (Box 90, Folder 631)
  - Colleges - Spelman College - Charter, 1888-1928 (Box 90, Folder 0631A)
  - Colleges - Spelman College - Property Purchase, 1931 (Box 90, Folder 632)
  - Colleges - Spelman College - Dedication of Sisters Chapel, 1927 (Box 90, Folder 0632A)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. speaks.
  - Colleges - Spelman College - Miss Read's History, 1954-1961 (Box 90, Folder 633)
    Office provides materials for history of Spelman College; contribution to help publish it.
  - Colleges - Spelman College - Miss Read's History, 1955-1961 (Box 90, Folder 633A)
  - Colleges - Spelman College - Dedication of Abby Aldrich Rockefeller Hall, 1952-1955 (Box 90, Folder 0633B)
    Laurance S. Rockefeller's speech; photos.
  - Colleges - Spelman College - 75th Anniversary Celebration, 1956 (Box 90, Folder 0633C)
    Laurance S. Rockefeller's speech; photos; contributions.
  - Colleges - Spelman College - Closed Material, 1953, 1956 (Box 90, Folder 633)
  - Colleges - Stanford University, 1931-1961 (Box 91, Folder 634)
    Reports on University activities and plans; John D. Rockefeller 3rd contributed $10,000 to Chair in honor of Sir George Samson. Correspondents include R. L. Wilbur, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., John D. Rockefeller 3rd, Arthur W. Packard.
  - Colleges - Stanford University - Hoover War Library, 1920-1937 (Box 91, Folder 0634A)
  - Colleges - Stanford University - Hoover War Library, 1937-1957 (Box 91, Folder 0634B)
  - Colleges - Stanford University - Hoover War Library, 1958 (Box 91, Folder 0634C)
  - Colleges - Stanford University - Industrial Relations, 1933-1942 (Box 91, Folder 635)
    John D. Rockefeller 3rd interest and contributions.
  - Colleges - State University of New York, 1949-1957 (Box 91, Folder 636)
    No family interest.
  - Colleges - Stephens Junior College, 1924-1948 (Box 91, Folder 637)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. gives $27,000 to support religious education at Stephens. Extended for several years; cut off in early 1930's. Total gifts: $62,000. Correspondents include Willard S. Richardson, Arthur W. Packard.
  - Colleges - Stephens Junior College - Pledge, 1924, 1924-1930 (Box 91, Folder 0637A)
  - Colleges - Stephens Junior College - Pledge, 1931, 1931-1934 (Box 91, Folder 0637B)
  - Colleges - Sweet Briar College, 1939-1959 (Box 91, Folder 638)
    Laurance S. Rockefeller spearheads $100,000 family contribution to development fund, 1955. Rockefeller-Guion Professorship in Chemistry. Correspondents include Laurance S. Rockefeller, David Rockefeller.
  - Colleges - Sweet Briar College, 1956-1960 (Box 91, Folder 0638A)
  - Colleges - Syracuse University, 1900-1952 (Box 91, Folder 639)
    John D. Rockefeller gave $100,000 at request of J. D. Archibald, 1901. Declined to give, 1905-1910. Frederick T. Gates opposed gift in 1910 because President J. K. Day was such a defender of Standard Oil Company; later requests declined. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Starr J. Murphy, John D. Archibald, Frederick T. Gates.
  - Colleges - Temple University, 1921-1957 (Box 92, Folder 640)
    Appeals for aid declined. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., John D. Rockefeller 3rd, Laurance S. Rockefeller, Willard S. Richardson, Dana S. Creel.
  - Colleges - Temple University - Chapel of the Four Chaplains, 1947-1955 (Box 92, Folder 0640A)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. gives $2,000 towards chapel; later appeals declined.
  - Colleges - Temple University - Laurance S. Rockefeller Materials, 1956-1957 (Box 92, Folder 0640B)
  - Colleges - Temple University - Institute for Direct Analysis, 1956-1958 (Box 92, Folder 641)
    Laurance S. Rockefeller interest in and contributions to psychiatric institute; Laurance S. Rockefeller made appeals for institute to others. Problems of Institute. Correspondents include Laurance S. Rockefeller, Arthur Jones.
  - Colleges - Temple University - Institute for Direct Analysis, 1958-1960 (Box 92, Folder 0641A)
  - Colleges - Temple University - Institute for the Study of Psychotherapy, 1960 (Box 92, Folder 642)
    Successor to Institute of Direct Analysis. Laurance S. Rockefeller contributions. Correspondents include Laurance S. Rockefeller, Arthur Jones.
  - Colleges - Union Theological Seminary
    Frederick T. Gates and Starr J. Murphy urge contribution in 1912; John D. Rockefeller gives $250,000. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. gives $1,000,000 in 1924, plus small gift towards chair in theological research. Further gifts by John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Laurance S. Rockefeller, and John D. Rockefeller 3rd. Invitations. Contributions towards Niebuhr chair. Activities of seminary. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Willard S. Richardson, Starr J. Murphy, Frederick T. Gates, Arthur W. Packard, Dana S. Creel, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Yorke Allen.
    - 1912-1918 (Box 92, Folder 643)
    - 1918-1936 (Box 92, Folder 644)
    - 1937-1948 (Box 92, Folder 645)
    - 1948 (Box 92, Folder 0645A)
    - 1949-1951 (Box 93, Folder 646)
    - 1951-1959 (Box 93, Folder 0646A)
    - 1960-1961 (Box 93, Folder 0646B)
  - Colleges - Union Theological Seminary - Gymnasium
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. buys property leased by Seminary, and deeds it over to Riverside Church. Correspondents include General Delafield, H. P. Van Dusen, John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
    - 1948-1951 (Box 93, Folder 647)
    - 1951-1955 (Box 93, Folder 648)
    - 1956-1957 (Box 93, Folder 649)
    - 1957 (Box 93, Folder 650)
    - 1957 (Box 93, Folder 651)
  - Colleges - Union Theological Seminary - October 1944 Pledge, 1944-1945 (Box 94, Folder 652)
    $125,000.
  - Colleges - Union Theological Seminary - Purchase of 49 Claremont Avenue, 1954-1961 (Box 94, Folder 0652A)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. conveys property to Sealantic Fund.
  - Colleges - Union Theological Seminary - Purchase of 49 Claremont Avenue, 1957-1958 (Box 94, Folder 0652B)
  - Colleges - Union Theological Seminary - March 31, 1955 Pledge (Box 94, Folder 653)
    $250,000.
  - Colleges - Union Theological Seminary - July 1959 Gift (Box 94, Folder 0653A)
    $1,000,000.
  - Colleges - Union Theological Seminary - Fosdick Visiting Professorship, 1952-1961 (Box 94, Folder 654)
  - Colleges - Union Theological Seminary - Program of Advanced Religious Studies, 1955 (Box 94, Folder 0654A)
  - Colleges - United Negro College Fund
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. chairman of National Advisory Committee. Progress of annual campaigns; selection of local chairmen; John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s interest in fund, and expressions of satisfaction with success of drives. Reports; invitations; John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s appeals for contributions. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. radio and television appearances. John D. Rockefeller 3rd's participation. Citation to John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., John D. Rockefeller 3rd, Arthur W. Packard, Dana S. Creel, Walker Hoving, Thomas Morgan, L. F. Kimball, A. P. Sloan.
    - 1944 (Box 94, Folder 655)
    - 1945-1946 (Box 94, Folder 0655A)
    - 1946 (Box 94, Folder 0655B)
    - 1947 (Box 94, Folder 0655C)
    - 1948 (Box 95, Folder 656)
    - 1949-1951 (Box 95, Folder 0656A)
    - 1950 (Box 95, Folder 657)
    - 1951 (Box 95, Folder 0657A)
    - 1952 (Box 95, Folder 658)
    - 1953 (Box 95, Folder 0658A)
    - 1954 (Box 95, Folder 659)
    - 1955-1961 (Box 95, Folder 0659A)
  - Colleges - United Negro College Fund - John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Speeches, 1944-1951 (Box 96, Folder 660)
    Radio, May 26, 1944; Rainbow Room, March 5, 1945; Radio, May 10, 1945; Radio, January 23, 1948; Radio, January 1951; Address, June 1951.
  - Colleges - United Negro College Fund - Luncheons, 1945-1946 (Box 96, Folder 661)
    June 12, 1945 in Rainbow Room; June 18, 1946.
  - Colleges - United Negro College Fund - Dinners, 1949-1952 (Box 96, Folder 0661A)
    May 3, 1949; March 5, 1951; March 31, 1952.
  - Colleges - United Negro College Fund - Tour, November 1952 (Box 96, Folder 0661B)
  - Colleges - United Negro College Fund - Opening Meetings, 1947-1948 (Box 96, Folder 662)
    April 14, 1947; April 1948.
  - Colleges - United Negro College Fund - Pledge 1948 (Box 96, Folder 0662A)
    To purchase building.
  - Colleges - United Negro College Fund - By-Laws, 1944 (Box 96, Folder 0662B)
  - Colleges - United Negro College Fund - Anniversary Celebration, 1953 (Box 96, Folder 0662C)
    In honor of General Education Board and Rockefeller family.
  - Colleges - United Negro College Fund - Letters of Criticism, 1944 (Box 96, Folder 662)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. criticized for holding Negro children.
  - Colleges - United Negro College Fund - L. F. Kimball Study, 1946-1947 (Box 96, Folder 663)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. has L. F. Kimball study operations of United Negro College Fund and implement improvements. No copy or report on study here. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., L. F. Kimball.
  - Colleges - United Negro College Fund - Mobilization Board, 1952-1954 (Box 96, Folder 664)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. gives $5,000,000 to Fund. President Eisenhower speaks at Fund luncheon. Campaign letters, replies. Use of funds. $17,500,000 raised. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., John D. Rockefeller 3rd, Dwight Eisenhower, F. D. Patterson, L. F. Kimball.
  - Colleges - United Negro College Fund - Mobilization Board, 1954-1956 (Box 96, Folder 0664A)
  - Colleges - United Negro College Fund - John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Letters of Appeal
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. writes asking contributions from friends and acquaintances for United Negro College Fund. Results of his appeal. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
    - 1944-1946 (Box 97, Folder 665)
    - 1944-1946 (Box 97, Folder 666)
    - 1944-1946 (Box 97, Folder 667)
    - 1944-1949 (Box 97, Folder 668)
    - 1944-1953 (Box 97, Folder 669)
    - 1945-1952 (Box 97, Folder 670)
    - 1946-1951 (Box 97, Folder 0670A)
  - Colleges - United Negro College Fund - Contributions Solicited by John D. Rockefeller, Jr., 1944-1959 (Box 98, Folder 671)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s views on solution of race relations problem. Rockefeller Brothers Fund gift, Nelson A. Rockefeller gifts; John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s annual contributions; gifts by Laura Rockefeller Case and Hope Rockefeller Spencer. 1961 Memos on East African Education Mission and proposed United Negro College Fund program in Africa. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Mrs. Winthrop W. Aldrich, Abby Aldrich Rockefeller.
    Open per KWR, June 2002.
  - Colleges - United Negro College Fund - Contributions from the Rockefeller Family, 1944-1961 (Box 98, Folder 0671A)
  - Colleges - United Negro College Fund - Contributions from the Rockefeller Family, 1948-1961 (Box 98, Folder 671B)
  - Colleges - United Negro College Fund - John D. Rockefeller 3rd, 1955-1959 (Box 98, Folder 672)
    John D. Rockefeller 3rd was chairman of Steering Committee, 1955-1956. Memo on Supreme Court desegregation decision and its effect on United Negro College Fund. John D. Rockefeller 3rd was chairman of National Committee of United Negro College Fund, 1958; Chairman of Corporations Gifts Committee, 1961. United Negro College Fund's tribute to John D. Rockefeller, Jr. in 1960 Annual Report. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller 3rd, William Trent, Stanley C. Hope.
  - Colleges - United Negro College Fund - John D. Rockefeller 3rd, 1959-1961 (Box 98, Folder 673)
  - Colleges - United Negro College Fund - John D. Rockefeller 3rd - October 1959 Dinner (Box 98, Folder 674)
    John D. Rockefeller 3rd was host; notes on his talk.
  - Colleges - United Negro College Fund - John D. Rockefeller 3rd - October 1960 Reception (Box 98, Folder 675)
    In honor of Presidents of member colleges.
  - Colleges - United Negro College Fund - John D. Rockefeller 3rd - October 1961 Dinner (Box 98, Folder 676)
    Notes on John D. Rockefeller 3rd's introductory address.
  - Colleges - United Negro College Fund - John D. Rockefeller 3rd - Dinner Colleges Invitations, 1961 (Box 99, Folder 677)
    Letters of invitation to United Negro College Fund dinner given by John D. Rockefeller 3rd on October 25, 1961.
  - Colleges - United Negro College Fund - John D. Rockefeller 3rd - Dinner Colleges Invitations, 1961 (Box 99, Folder 678)
  - Colleges - United Negro College Fund - Printed Materials, 1950 (Box 99, Folder 679)
    United Negro College Fund's "Instruments for Unity."
  - Colleges - University of California, 1950-1961 (Box 99, Folder 680)
    John D. Rockefeller 3rd's recommendation that school participate in cooperative program with University of Indonesia. John D. Rockefeller 3rd declines to contribute to Memorial for Norman Buchanan. 1961 Report by President Kerr on National Labor Policy. Correspondents include Clark Kerr, Robert Sproul, John D. Rockefeller 3rd.
  - Colleges - University of California - Horace M. Albright Lectureship, 1959-1960 (Box 99, Folder 681)
    Contributions by John D. Rockefeller, Jr., David Rockefeller, Laurance S. Rockefeller, John D. Rockefeller 3rd to establish lectures on conservation.